Marc Llopart Enajas

🧥 Gelida, Barcelona, Spain (Open to relocation) 🜙 +34 633959561 🛮 🗷 llopartdata@gmail.com

SUMMARY — Data Scientist with a strong background in computational mathematics and data analytics, specializing in machine learning, blockchain technologies, and data visualization.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Languages Python, R, SQL, MongoDB, Javascript, Bash,

Solidity, Git

Cloud AWS, Azure

Libraries Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Statsmodel, Matplotlib, Streamlit OS Debian, Ubuntu, MacOS, Windows

EXPERIENCE

Banco Sabadell Dec 2023 - Present

Data Scientist (Economic Capital & ICAAP)

Sant Cugat del Vallés, Barcelona (Hybrid)

- Developed and implemented models to assess and quantify operational risks, non-performing credit, climatic risk, and sectorial concentration.
- Conducted thorough data analysis to identify patterns, trends, and anomalies impacting the bank's risk exposure.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams on the ICAAP report to analyze the bank's solvency.

Feb 2023 - Jul 2023 **Perpetuum Progress**

Web3 Researcher & Developer

Remote

Remote

- Researched B2B payment methods for Web3 Data Exchange focused on the Mobility Industry.
- Implemented a Private Blockchain network based on Proof of Authority (PoA).
- Integrated Cross-Chain functionalities in a private blockchain.

Aily Labs Jul 2023 - Sep 2023

Data Scientist Internship

Barcelona, Spain (Hybrid)

- Developed a Recommender Engine from implicit feedback to enhance user retention on internal App.
- Created tables and views using SQL and Python.
- Coded new OOP classes and functions to process data and develop scalable features.

Freelancer - Clash Royale League

May 2021 - May 2022

Data Scientist

- Prepared data from players using Excel to assist in deck choices.

- Delivered reports with key strategies for games based on data analysis.
- Improved player performance and consistency, achieving Top 6 in the World Finals.

SK Gaming Jul 2018 - Dec 2020

Data Analyst

Remote

Delivered reports for match strategies based on previous data studies.

- Prepared competition data using Excel and Google Studio and assisted in team strategy development.
- Scouted new players during off-season periods to enhance team performance.
- Achievements include Top 2 in the 2020 World Finals.

EDUCATION

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya

Oct 2023 - Oct 2024

Master's Degree in Blockchain Technologies

Barcelona

Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona

2019-2023

Bachelor of Science in Computational Mathematics and Data Analytics Thesis Title: Developing a Payment Method for a Web3 Mobility Data Space Barcelona

NOVA School of Science & Technology

2022-2023

Semester Abroad Erasmus+ Program Program: Data Science and Big Data

Lisbon, Portugal

Languages

- English Advanced
- Spanish Native
- Catalan Native